Guide to the William Mangin papers, 1951-1990.
Mangin, William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William Mangin papers, 1951-1990.
8413
Mangin, William
7 cubic feet.
Photographs, research material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files, publications, clippings, field notes and field notebooks, photographs, and slides of Vicos and the Barriadas.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
William Mangin acted as Field Director of the Vicos experimental station from 1952-1953. He also was involved in the Barriadas in Lima and the Peace Corps in Peru and served as professor of anthropology at Syracuse University. His research interests included squatter settlements and mental health issues in Peru.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files, publications, clippings, field notes and field notebooks, photographs, and slides of Vicos and the Barriadas.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Mangin, William; Cornell Peru Project.
Subjects:
Anthropology -- Research.; Urbanization -- Peru -- Lima.; Squatter settlements -- Peru -- Lima.; Mental health -- Peru.
Places:
Lima (Peru) -- Social conditions.; Vicos (Peru)
Form and Genre Terms:
Field notes.; Photographs.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Miscellaneous Files and Documents
Series II. Mental Health Documents
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Slides
Series V. Audio
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Miscellaneous Files and Documents
  - "Long-Term Field Research in Social Anthropology" typed chapter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and publications, 1956-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vicos: Sogo Ewn (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Typed paper (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William Mangin notes and publications, 1951-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Vicos notes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vicos publications, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Vicos, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vicos miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mangin Vicos letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vicos Method, 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Revised Vicos paper, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vicos, Dobyns (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Vicos, Stowe (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous papers and publications (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Vicos Cornell paper, 1950s, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Vicos Peace Corps (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes, AAA (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Human Organization", notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Vazquez papers (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Vicos miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 24-26)
  - Paper on the Good and the Bad Patron (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - William Stein papers, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Barriadas (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mendocita (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Goldschmidt, Aldine book (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, publications and papers, 1950-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7-14)
  - Publications and clippings, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Publications, 1950s-1960s (Box 6)
  - Notebooks, 1950s-1960s (Box 7)
  - Note cards, 1950s-1960s (Box 8-10)
- Series II. Mental Health Documents
  - Woolman self inst. materials, Alcoholism. NIMH grant, Barriada (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mariscal Castilla, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mendocita (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous mental health materials (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Barriada Mariscal Castilla census (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Lima Peru case studies, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Research grant application, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Census and surveys, Mariscal Castilla, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notecards (Box 3)
- Series III. Photographs
  - Vicos, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Vicos, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Huarez, Ancash, Carhuaz, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cuzco, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Barriada, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mariscol Castilla, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - Mendocita, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Lima, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
  - Negatives, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Unknown, 1950s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - Unknown, 1950s-1960s (Box 6)
- Series IV. Slides
  - Barriadas, Vicos, Marcara, Squatters around the world, and miscellaneous, 1950s-1980s (Box 11)
- Series V. Audio
  - Vicos, 1958; 1967 (Box 11)